class QuestionModel{
  final String question;
  final List<String> options;
  final correctAnswerIndex;
  final String Solution;

  const QuestionModel({
    required this.question,
    required this.options,
    required this.correctAnswerIndex,
    required this.Solution,
});
}


List<QuestionModel> questions = [
   QuestionModel(question: "1. What is the primary goal of cognitive computing?",
      options: [
        "A. Mimicking human-like thinking processes",
        "B. Eliminating human cognitive abilities",
        "C. Randomly processing information",
        "D. Ignoring cognitive functions"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 0,
    Solution: 'The primary goal of cognitive computing is to mimic human-like thinking processes. It involves creating systems that can understand, reason, learn, and interact with users in a way that resembles human cognition.'
  ),

QuestionModel(question: "2. Which technology is often integrated into cognitive computing systems for natural language understanding?",
      options: [
        "A. Natural Language Processing (NLP)",
        "B. Computer Vision",
        "C. Robotics",
        "D. Virtual Reality"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 0,
    Solution: 'Natural Language Processing (NLP) is often integrated into cognitive computing systems for natural language understanding. It enables machines to interpret and respond to human language, facilitating communication.'
  ),

QuestionModel(question: "3. How does machine learning contribute to cognitive computing?",
      options: [
        "A. By enabling systems to learn from data and improve over time",
        "B. By ignoring data and relying on fixed rules",
        "C. By eliminating learning capabilities",
        "D. By randomly processing information"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 0,
    Solution: 'Machine learning contributes to cognitive computing by enabling systems to learn from data and improve over time. It allows the system to adapt and enhance its performance based on experience and new information.'
  ),

QuestionModel(question: "4. What role does pattern recognition play in cognitive computing?",
      options: [
        "A. Identifying meaningful patterns in data",
        "B. Ignoring patterns in data",
        "C. Randomly processing information",
        "D. Eliminating data patterns"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 0,
    Solution: 'Pattern recognition in cognitive computing plays the role of identifying meaningful patterns in data. It involves recognizing regularities or structures in data, contributing to the system\'s understanding and decision-making.'
  ),

QuestionModel(question: "5. Which aspect of cognitive computing involves understanding and responding to human emotions?",
      options: [
        "A. Affective computing",
        "B. Cognitive robotics",
        "C. Augmented reality",
        "D. Virtual assistants"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 0,
    Solution: 'The aspect of cognitive computing that involves understanding and responding to human emotions is known as affective computing. It focuses on recognizing and interpreting human emotions for more empathetic interactions.'
  ),

QuestionModel(question: "6. What is the significance of context awareness in cognitive computing?",
      options: [
        "A. Understanding and adapting to the surrounding context",
        "B. Ignoring contextual information",
        "C. Randomly processing information",
        "D. Eliminating contextual factors"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 0,
    Solution: 'Context awareness in cognitive computing is significant for understanding and adapting to the surrounding context. It involves considering the broader environment and circumstances to enhance the system\'s responses.'
  ),

QuestionModel(question: "7. Which technology enables cognitive computing systems to interpret and analyze visual information from the world?",
      options: [
        "A. Computer Vision",
        "B. Natural Language Processing (NLP)",
        "C. Robotics",
        "D. Virtual Reality"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 0,
    Solution: 'Computer Vision enables cognitive computing systems to interpret and analyze visual information from the world. It involves the extraction of meaningful insights from images or video data.'
  ),

QuestionModel(question: "8. How does cognitive computing differ from traditional computing approaches?",
      options: [
        "A. It emphasizes human-like thinking processes",
        "B. It relies on fixed rules and algorithms",
        "C. It ignores learning capabilities",
        "D. It randomly processes information"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 0,
    Solution: 'Cognitive computing differs from traditional computing approaches by emphasizing human-like thinking processes. Unlike traditional computing, cognitive computing systems can learn, reason, and adapt based on data and experiences.'
  ),

QuestionModel(question: "9. What is the role of reasoning in cognitive computing?",
      options: [
        "A. Drawing conclusions and making inferences",
        "B. Ignoring logical processes",
        "C. Randomly processing information",
        "D. Eliminating reasoning abilities"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 0,
    Solution: 'Reasoning in cognitive computing involves drawing conclusions and making inferences based on available information. It enables the system to logically process data and arrive at meaningful insights.'
  ),

QuestionModel(question: "10. How does cognitive computing contribute to personalized user experiences?",
      options: [
        "A. By understanding individual preferences and behaviors",
        "B. By ignoring user preferences",
        "C. By randomly processing information",
        "D. By eliminating personalization"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 0,
    Solution: 'Cognitive computing contributes to personalized user experiences by understanding individual preferences and behaviors. It tailors interactions and content based on user-specific information for a more customized experience.'
  ),

QuestionModel(question: "11. What is the role of self-learning in cognitive computing?",
      options: [
        "A. Systems improving and adapting over time",
        "B. Ignoring learning capabilities",
        "C. Randomly processing information",
        "D. Eliminating self-improvement"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 0,
    Solution: 'The role of self-learning in cognitive computing involves systems improving and adapting over time. It allows the system to learn from experiences, data, and user interactions, continuously enhancing its performance.'
  ),

QuestionModel(question: "12. In cognitive computing, what does the term 'cognition' refer to?",
      options: [
        "A. The process of acquiring knowledge and understanding",
        "B. Ignoring the acquisition of knowledge",
        "C. Randomly processing information",
        "D. Eliminating understanding processes"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 0,
    Solution: 'In cognitive computing, the term \'cognition\' refers to the process of acquiring knowledge and understanding. It involves the ability to perceive, learn, reason, and adapt in a manner similar to human cognition.'
  ),

QuestionModel(question: "13. How does cognitive computing address ambiguity and uncertainty in data?",
      options: [
        "A. By handling uncertain and ambiguous information",
        "B. By ignoring uncertainty",
        "C. By randomly processing information",
        "D. By eliminating ambiguous data"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 0,
    Solution: 'Cognitive computing addresses ambiguity and uncertainty in data by handling uncertain and ambiguous information. It is designed to make sense of incomplete or conflicting data, simulating human-like adaptability.'
  ),

QuestionModel(question: "14. What distinguishes cognitive computing from traditional expert systems?",
      options: [
        "A. Cognitive computing learns from data and experiences",
        "B. Traditional expert systems rely on fixed rules",
        "C. Cognitive computing randomly processes information",
        "D. Traditional expert systems eliminate learning capabilities"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 0,
    Solution: 'What distinguishes cognitive computing from traditional expert systems is that cognitive computing learns from data and experiences, whereas traditional expert systems rely on fixed rules and knowledge bases.'
  ),

QuestionModel(question: "15. How does cognitive computing enhance decision-making processes?",
      options: [
        "A. By analyzing data and providing insights",
        "B. By ignoring data analysis",
        "C. By randomly processing information",
        "D. By eliminating decision-making capabilities"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 0,
    Solution: 'Cognitive computing enhances decision-making processes by analyzing data and providing insights. It aids in understanding complex information, identifying patterns, and offering valuable recommendations for informed decisions.'
  ),

QuestionModel(question: "16. What is the significance of natural language understanding in cognitive computing?",
      options: [
        "A. Enabling machines to comprehend and respond to human language",
        "B. Ignoring human language",
        "C. Randomly processing information",
        "D. Eliminating language understanding"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 0,
    Solution: 'The significance of natural language understanding in cognitive computing is in enabling machines to comprehend and respond to human language. It facilitates meaningful interactions and communication between humans and machines.'
  ),

QuestionModel(question: "17. How does cognitive computing contribute to problem-solving?",
      options: [
        "A. By reasoning and generating solutions",
        "B. By ignoring problem-solving capabilities",
        "C. By randomly processing information",
        "D. By eliminating reasoning processes"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 0,
    Solution: 'Cognitive computing contributes to problem-solving by reasoning and generating solutions. It leverages its understanding of data and context to propose effective solutions to complex problems.'
  ),

QuestionModel(question: "18. What is the primary role of machine learning algorithms in cognitive computing?",
      options: [
        "A. Enabling systems to learn from data",
        "B. Ignoring learning capabilities",
        "C. Randomly processing information",
        "D. Eliminating machine learning"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 0,
    Solution: 'The primary role of machine learning algorithms in cognitive computing is enabling systems to learn from data. It allows the system to improve its performance, adapt to new information, and enhance its capabilities.'
  ),

QuestionModel(question: "19. How does cognitive computing impact data interpretation?",
      options: [
        "A. Enhancing the understanding of complex data",
        "B. Ignoring data interpretation",
        "C. Randomly processing information",
        "D. Eliminating data understanding"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 0,
    Solution: 'Cognitive computing impacts data interpretation by enhancing the understanding of complex data. It goes beyond basic data processing, providing insights and context to support informed decision-making.'
  ),

QuestionModel(question: "20. What distinguishes cognitive computing systems in terms of adaptability?",
      options: [
        "A. They can adapt based on experiences and feedback",
        "B. They ignore adaptability",
        "C. They randomly process information",
        "D. They eliminate adaptive capabilities"
      ],
    correctAnswerIndex: 0,
    Solution: 'What distinguishes cognitive computing systems in terms of adaptability is that they can adapt based on experiences and feedback. They continuously learn and evolve to improve their performance over time.'
  ),

];